<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Eki.Lab Blog</title>
        <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Eki.Lab Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Newsletter for April 2022]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/05/02/newsletter_April-2022</link>
            <guid>Newsletter for April 2022</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are now at the start of May and we release our 4th Newsletter! Ranging from podcasts to tutorials, this Newsletter is made for practicioners!]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deploying your Data Science app to the Cloud]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/04/21/docker</link>
            <guid>Deploying your Data Science app to the Cloud</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Let's explore how we, at Ekimetrics, automate the deployment of our data apps on the cloud. This article will gather elements from our internal & external workshops presented at Datacraft and also the video presenting some docker best practices for industrialization. ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Newsletter for March 2022]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/03/30/newsletter_March-2022</link>
            <guid>Newsletter for March 2022</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Ekimetrics is pleased to release its third Newsletter for the year 2022! A new feature has now been added which is a special section detailing some news that we would like to share but are not specifically linked to one of our main categories. As usual, do not hesitate to check the links added and of course using it live during your projects!]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Power BI - Improve your development process by using multiple environments]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/03/16/powerbi_multiple_environments</link>
            <guid>Power BI - Improve your development process by using multiple environments</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ Learn in this article why and how to use different environments when developing products in Power BI. ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Newsletter for February 2022]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/02/28/newsletter_Feb-2022</link>
            <guid>Newsletter for February 2022</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Ekimetrics is pleased to release its second Newsletter of 2022! This cheat sheet will brief you quickly about the latest news in the fields of Data Science, Machine Learning, Data Engineering and Application Development. Warning this one is particularly ruled by DeepMind so be prepared!]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demand Forecasting - Improving Supply Chain operations in uncertain times]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/02/22/demand_forecasting_supply</link>
            <guid>Demand Forecasting - Improving Supply Chain operations in uncertain times</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Learn in this article how we industrialized a solution for warehouse demand forecasting to help Operations managers better allocate resources for more than 20.000 referenced products]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ekimetrics implements Data Mesh. Here is why, and why you should join us]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/02/09/ekimetrics_implements_data_mesh</link>
            <guid>Ekimetrics implements Data Mesh. Here is why, and why you should join us</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This article describes one of the inspirational patterns that drive our projects’ data architectures, the Data Mesh.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building a datalake - Part 1 - Usable, Useful, Used, or how to avoid dataswamp and empty shell traps]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/02/07/building_datalake_part_1</link>
            <guid>Building a datalake - Part 1 - Usable, Useful, Used, or how to avoid dataswamp and empty shell traps</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In this article, learn how to create your first datalake following best practices in order to make it robust, evolutive and central to your company's information architecture, as well as take advantage of the opportunities it presents.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Which AutoML platform to choose to start your Data Science project?]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/01/27/automl_benchmark</link>
            <guid>Which AutoML platform to choose to start your Data Science project?</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[How do Automatic Machine Learning solutions work? What are the most popular AutoML solutions out there, and what do you need to know about them to make the right choice for your use case? Find answers to these questions and many others in this article.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hackathon Stories - Ensuring access to affordable and clean energy]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2022/01/06/hackathon</link>
            <guid>Hackathon Stories - Ensuring access to affordable and clean energy</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Read this article to see how and why Ekimetrics organize hackathons to foster creativity, innovation and team work in our Data teams. Also learn important tips for organizing your own hackathons.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Customer Journey Clustering - How to use sequential modeling techniques to handle customer journey data]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2021/12/22/cjc</link>
            <guid>Customer Journey Clustering - How to use sequential modeling techniques to handle customer journey data</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Enrich your understanding of customer journeys through clustering using  image embedding, autoencoders and unsupervised learning.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introduction to Pyepidemics - epidemiological modeling in Python]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/introduction-pyepidemics</link>
            <guid>introduction-pyepidemics</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We created Pyepidemics, an open-source library to simulate epidemics (SIR, SEIHDR, COVID19). We detail in this article what you can build with the library.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solving the Traveling Salesman Problem with Reinforcement Learning]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/2021/11/03/tsp</link>
            <guid>Solving the Traveling Salesman Problem with Reinforcement Learning</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A practical use of Reinforcement Learning and the Q-Learning algorithm to solve the Traveling Salesman Problem]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Deploying a Python Dash application for beginners]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/dash-deployment</link>
            <guid>dash-deployment</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Learn the basics of application deployment from simple examples on Heroku to creating Docker containers]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome to the new Ekimetrics Tech website!]]></title>
            <link>https://ekimetrics.github.io/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to EkiLab website - the Ekimetrics technology & innovation blog and website!]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>